[Music]
Hey guys, Pastor Ivor Meyers here and uh
in this video we're going to be taking a
look at a very special and unique
challenge regarding the question of
whether the Quran is the final
revelation of God's
And also, was Muhammad actually sent by
God? Um, this challenge
is a unique challenge. You have probably
never heard this challenge before. If
you're a Muslim, I encourage you to
watch with an open mind. If you're a
Christian, I encourage you to watch
because this is going to be very helpful
uh in terms of dialoguing uh with
someone who may be Muslim. So, we're
going to call this challenge the
mathematical
chain challenge or I might even say the
mathematical chain crisis. And what
we're going to do is even though we're
going to focus on um the Quran and uh
the prophet Muhammad, the so-called
prophet Muhammad,
um I want to throw in the mix uh Joseph
Smith and the Book of Mormons.
So, we're going to kind of address both
of them at once, but you're going to see
they're actually very similar in their
claims. Um, so let's uh get ready to
jump in because this is going to be
mindblowing. I promise you. Uh, we're
going to take a journey through the
Bible. You're going to see how God
operates on a very specific pattern. And
the challenge is very simple. If the
Quran and Muhammad and Joseph Smith and
the Book of Mormons fits this pattern,
then we may know that they were sent of
God. If neither fit the pattern, then we
may know without question that neither
were sent by God. So, let's check this
pattern out. We're going to go ahead and
begin with the book of Genesis. Now, um
we're going to start with two characters
in particular, Noah and Methuselah. So,
let's go ahead and break this down. We
know that in the book of Genesis, God
speaks of a flood that is to come and he
sends a prophet by the name of Noah.
Now, he tells Noah that mankind has a
specific time. There's a time prophecy
allotted to man in the days of Noah.
That time period is
120 years. Now we can read about this in
Genesis chapter 6 and verse three. The
Bible says, "And the Lord said, "My
spirit shall not always strive with man,
for that he is also flesh, yet his days
shall be 120 years." So there is the
time prophecy. We're going to call it
the divine mathematics of God. He says,
"Man has 120 years." So Noah preaches
120 years. And at the end of that 120
years, the flood is going to come. Now,
let's go ahead and look at something
very, very interesting in Genesis
chapter 5. It's the genealogy, Noah's
genealogy. And what I want you to see
here is in Genesis 5:2, they're going to
speak about a person by the name of
Methuselah.
So the Bible says here and Methuselah
lived in 187 years and begat Lamech. So
let me summarize this. Methuselah was
187 years old when he fathered Lamek.
Now verse 27 goes on to say and all the
days of Methuselah were 969
years old. So Methuselah died when he
was 969 years old. Now I want you to
follow this math carefully. Let's go
ahead and we're going to read uh verse
28 and 29. The Bible says, "And Lamech
lived 182 years and begat a son and he
called his name Noah."
So Lamek is 182 years old when he
fathers Noah. So what does this mean?
Why are we looking at this math? Well,
Methuselah would have been 369
years old when Noah was born.
Now, why is this significant? Because in
Genesis 7 and verse 6, the Bible says,
"And Noah was 600 years old when the
floods of the waters were upon the
earth." Meaning if we take 369
the age of Methuselah when Noah is born
and then we add 600 years that means
this is the very year that the flood
comes we will find something very
interesting. Methuselah is 969
years old when the flood occurs. Meaning
in the very year that the flood
happened, Methuselah died. He dies
before the flood. In the very year he
dies, in that very year the flood
happens. Why is this significant?
If you look at the name Methuselah,
according to Theer's dictionary, here's
what his name means. When he dies, there
shall be an emission. In other words,
when he dies, something is coming. When
he dies, it will come. In essence,
Methuselah was like a walking prophecy
that confirmed
the prophet Noah and what he was
preaching for 120 years. In the very
year that Methuselah died, the flood
came. Why is this significant?
Because in this we see how God operates
and we're going to see this very pattern
throughout the entire Bible. So God sent
an initiated prophet that is Noah and
then he gives him a time period 120
years. He gives him divine math
120 years. And at the end of that 120
years, there is a a sign uh if you will
of that very prophecy going to meet its
fulfillment. Methuselah is the
fulfillment, the sign that verifies
that God's word was true.
Noah is the initiated prophet.
Methuselah, his death is the sign that
that verified that 120 year period. All
right, this is pre flood.
Now, we're going to ask ourselves a
question. Does God carry this pattern
throughout the rest of the Bible? I want
you to just pay attention. Watch
carefully, you guys. And I want you to
notice something very important here. In
the book of Galatians chapter 1 6, the
Bible says,"I marvel that you are so
soon removed from him that called you
into the grace of Christ unto another
gospel, which is not another. But there
be some that trouble you and would
pervert the gospel of Christ. But though
we or an angel from heaven preach any
other gospel unto you, that we than that
which we have preached unto you, let him
be accursed." Let me ask you a question.
Let's say that a prophet arose
60 years into Noah's preaching and this
prophet uh was able to perform miracles
and he even came with a special book
that he said God gave him and this
prophet said listen I am here to let you
know that the flood will be happening in
just a few years.
What would you be able to know
automatically?
That prophet doesn't fit the time period
that he doesn't fit the math that God
gave to Noah. Therefore, you don't need
to listen to that person because God has
not sent that individual. Are you with
me?
God's sign would come at the fulfillment
of the time of that prophecy. So someone
comes along and says, "Uh, well, I know
what Noah said, but I think that this is
going to happen a lot sooner." We would
know that person was not sent of God. He
could have a special book. He could have
performed miracles. We know that that
person was not sent of God. Okay. So,
let's move on and let's see. Does God
continue this pattern? Let's go to
the next prophet on the scene, which is
Abraham. Because this is now post flood.
God calls a man by the name of Abraham
or Abram on the scene. Does God give
Abraham a prophecy? The answer is yes.
It is the 400year prophecy found in
Genesis 15 and verse 13. The Bible says,
"And he said unto Abram, know of
assurityity that thy seed shall be a
stranger in a land that is not theirs,
and shall serve them, and they shall
afflict them 400 years, and also that
nation whom they shall serve will judge,
and afterward they and afterward shall
they come out with great substance." So
we see here that God gives Abraham a
prophecy and he tells him 400 years.
Does someone come at the end of that 400
years to verify the prophecy? The answer
is yes. In Exodus chapter 2:10, we read
about a man by the name of Moses. We
know that Moses comes at the end of just
as God had prophesied. Moses comes in
fulfillment of the prophecy and he is
the one that will deliver the children
of Israel out of captivity. So I'm going
to ask you a question again. Let's say
that someone comes on the scene 200
years into their captivity. And he says,
"Hey, God has sent me with a message.
You are about to be delivered." What
would we know? This person could have
claimed that God gave them a book. They
could have performed miracles. What
would we know about that so-called
prophet? we would know that God did not
send him because God already gave a
mathematical description, a mathematical
chain if you will, that lets us know
we're to be looking for something
special to happen at this time.
Not a hundred years before, not 200
years before, at that time. Are y'all
with me so far? So
again we see something quite amazing
here. We see God sending an initiated
prophet and then a prophet that will
verify at the end of the time period
given to the initiated prophet. He comes
in verification so you can know Moses
was sent by God. We know that. Why?
Because he came at the right time. Now
what does this mean? Very simply, it
means this. When Moses
writes, you know, his books, Genesis,
Exodus, Leviticus, uh, Numbers,
Deuteronomy, we can trust that those
books are divinely inspired because they
come from the man who was sent by God.
And we know he was sent by God because
he came at the right time. Are y'all
with me? If someone came 200 years
earlier and said, "I was sent by God and
and God has sent me to let you know that
you're about to be delivered in a year,
two years, five years, 10 years." We
would know that that person is not
speaking on behalf of God. Are y'all
with me? So, we have Abraham, the
initiated prophet. We have a time
period, a mathematical time period, if
you will, 400 years. And then we have
the fulfillment prophet which is Moses.
Okay. So
we know then that Moses is a verified
prophet and we can trust the books of
Moses. Let's keep moving. Let's I I hope
you see where we're going with this.
Does God give Moses a prophecy? Well,
the answer is yes. You're going to see
that chain continues, right? So from uh
from uh Noah to Methuselah, Abraham to
Moses and now you're going to see Moses
himself gives a few prophecies, two in
particular. Let's look at those two
prophecies.
Prophecy number one, uh we'll read from
Leviticus 26 32-34. Now, I want you to
understand that this prophecy we're
about to read, given by Moses, was given
to the children of Israel, letting them
know if they were disobedient to the
will of God, something was going to
happen to them. And we're going to read
it in these verses here. So, Leviticus
26:32,
it says, "And I will bring the land,"
this is God speaking here, "I will bring
the land into desolation, and your
enemies which dwell therein shall be
astonished at it. and I will scatter you
among the heathen, and will draw out a
sword after you, and your land shall be
desolate, and your cities waste. Then
shall the land enjoy her Sabbaths. As
long as it lith desolate, and you be in
your enemy's land, even then shall the
land rest and enjoy her Sabbaths. So
Moses is here prophesying that if the
children of Israel were to be
disobedient, they would be scattered.
they would be uh destroyed by a foreign
nation, a foreign kingdom. That's
prophecy number one.
Let's go to prophecy number two.
Prophecy number two is found in
Deuteronomy 18 and 19. And this is Moses
speaking. He's saying or this is God
speaking to Moses. I will raise them up
a prophet from among their brethren like
unto thee, and will put my words in his
mouth, and he shall speak unto them all
that I shall command him. And it shall
come to pass that whosoever will not
hearken unto my words, which he has
which which he shall speak in my name, I
will require it of him. So, prophet num
prophecy number one, if you disobey,
you're going into captivity. Prophecy
number two, I'm sending a prophet among
you. Now, we know that many prophets
came through Israel. So, God is speaking
here about a very specific
prophet. There were many prophets in the
Old Testament. God is speaking about a
very specific prophet. Notice the book
of Acts 3:22. The Bible says here, "For
Moses truly said unto the fathers, a
prophet shall the Lord your God raise
unto you of your brethren, like unto me,
him shall you hear in all things
whatsoever he shall say unto you." And
it shall come to pass that every soul
which will not hear that prophet shall
be destroyed from among the people. Now
listen to this next verse very
carefully. Yay. And all the prophets
from Samuel and those that follow after
many as have spoken have likewise
foretold of these days. So what the book
of acts 3 22- 24 is saying is that since
Moses and Samuel would have been the
next prophet after Moses
from Samuel
all the way through all the prophets
have spoken about this same prophet to
come.
All of them they've spoken about this
prophet, this same prophet in
Deuteronomy 18:18. Now, let me just give
a little side note here, which is very
interesting.
Muslims believe that Muhammad is that
prophet. Mormons believe that Joseph
Smith is that prophet. Very interesting.
Both groups of people go to Deuteronomy
18 to claim that the prophet like unto
Moses is Muhammad for Muslims. And for
Mormons, they claim that it is Joseph
Smith. All right.
So here we have these two prophecies.
One, the destruction of Jerusalem. Two,
a prophet is coming.
What happens is we go to the book of
Jeremiah and we find that Jeremiah along
with other prophets are verifying what
Moses is talking about. But Jeremiah
specifically adds a time period, a
mathematic chain if you will, amplifying
Moses's prophecy. So he's taking what
Moses said, speaking in line with what
the previous prophet said and said and
and he's saying, listen, the children of
Israel are going to spend 70 years in
Babylon. You see it right there on the
screen. Jeremiah 25:11. And this whole
land shall be a desolation and an
astonishment, and these nations shall
serve the king of Babylon 70 years. He's
referring to Babylon uh gaining dominion
over the territories including
Jerusalem. So Jeremiah puts a time
period on this prophecy. The question
is, did Jerusalem end up going into
captivity for 70 years? The answer is
yes. Notice 2 Chronicles 36:15. The
Bible says, "And the Lord God of their
fathers sent to them by his messengers."
So, who would his messengers be? That
would be all the prophets from Samuel
all the way up to Jeremiah.
He sent them uh rising up at times and
sending them because he had compassion
on his people and on his dwelling place.
But they mocked the messengers of God
and despised his words and misused his
prophets until the wrath of the Lord
arose against his people till there was
no remedy. All these prophets were
speaking right in line with Moses. So
what does this tell us? What it tells
us, beloved, is that not only can we
trust the books of Moses, but we can
trust the prophets who came after him
because they are all speaking the same
thing Moses spoke. They're all talking
about this prophet to come and they're
all warning of this destruction to come
upon Jerusalem. And now they go a step
further and put a time stamp on it.
Well, 2 Chronicles 36:20 reads, "And
them that had escaped from the sword
carried he away to Babylon, where they
were servants to him and his sons until
the reign of the kingdom of Persia, to
fulfill the word of the Lord by the
mouth of Jeremiah until the land had
enjoyed her Sabbaths. For as long as she
laid desolate, she kept Sabbath to
fulfill three score and 10 years."
That's 70 years. So beloved, I want
listen again.
If a prophet arose and said, "Hey, you
guys aren't going to spend 70 years in
captivity. You're only going to spend 40
years. And I'm the prophet that is here
to tell you that you're about to be set
free from your captivity 30 years
early." What would we know about that
so-called prophet? we would know that
that prophet was not sent because he was
not speaking in line with the
mathematical equation of God. Are you
with me? Are y'all following?
So, here's a question. God gives this
70-year prophecy. He he gives it
initially through Moses, though Moses
doesn't put a time on it. Jeremiah comes
along and says it's going to be 70
years. And then, lo and behold, they go
into captivity. They're there for 70
years. The question now is does God send
a prophet that will that will be at the
end of that 70 years that acknowledges
the punishment of is of Jerusalem. Well,
let's go let's go y'all to the book of
Daniel.
You see, in Daniel, who is Daniel? First
of all, Daniel was one of the children
of Israel who was taken into captivity
when Babylon destroyed Jerusalem.
And while Daniel is in Babylonian
captivity, during that 70-year period,
he receives a series of prophecies,
time prophecies. Are y'all seeing this?
God is letting us know at every step of
the way, every prophet he sends. and
those in between those time periods are
all in line with that particular time
period, that particular mathematic
prophecy.
So let's look at what Daniel chapter 9
verse 1 and 2 says. Daniel speaking says
in the first year of Darius the son of
Ahazerus of the seeds of the Mes which
was made king over the realm of the
Calaldanss in the first year of his
reign um I Daniel understood by books
the number of the years whereof the word
of the Lord came to Jeremiah the prophet
that he would accomplish how long y'all
70 years in the desolations of
Jerusalem.
Daniel continues on. He's now praying to
God and he's he's rehearsing as it were
the sins of Israel. And notice what he
says in verse 13 and 14. As it is
written in the law of Moses, all this
evil is come upon us, yet we made not
our prayer before the Lord our God, that
we might turn from our iniquities and
understand thy truth. Therefore hath the
Lord wa watched upon this evil upon the
evil and brought it upon us. For the
Lord our God is righteous in all his
works which he doeth. For we obeyed not
his voice. Daniel is literally saying
here. What Moses said and what Jeremiah
said after him is being fulfilled has
been fulfilled. Daniel comes at that at
the ending of that seven-year period and
he is he is confirming
he is affirming the 70 years given by
Jeremiah who got that prophecy from
Moses.
I hope y'all are seeing this. This lets
us know, beloved, that we can trust the
book of Daniel.
We can trust the book of Daniel because
Daniel is writing right on time. He is
there right on time and he he points
back to this mathematical chain.
Are y'all following this? So, we got the
the 120 years of the flood. We have the
400 years of captivity, the children of
Israel. We have the 70 years of
Babylonian captivity. And now we're in
the book of Daniel. And the question for
us is, does Daniel give a prophecy
that is going to advance us further down
this timeline?
Check it out, y'all. I want you to see
this. We got the initiator prophet Moses
and the fulfillment prophets, Jeremiah,
Ezekiel, Daniel, Isaiah. All of them,
beloved, are right in line with what
Moses said.
They are right in line with the prophecy
of Moses. Number one, that a m that that
that a a a prophet is coming and none of
them claim to be that prophet. Number
two, that the children of Israel will go
into captivity because of their
rebellion. And there's a time period
connected with this, which brings us
down to the book of Daniel. So now the
question is, does Daniel himself receive
a prophecy that pushes us into the
future? And the answer is yes. It is
called the 70week
prophecy or the 490year
prophecy. Now, by far, this is the most
detailed prophecy of all the prophecies
we've spoken of up to this point. And
there's a reason why. So, what we're
going to do, we're going to spend the
rest of this time on this one prophecy.
And we can spend a whole segment,
multiple segments on this prophecy
because it is so detailed. But for the
purpose of our challenge, we're not
going to do that. We're going to try to
juice this prophecy down and and and
just look at the essential things we
need to understand. You may have never
heard of this prophecy before, but I
just want you to just stay with me,
okay? Let's look at this prophecy. The
Bible says in Daniel 9 verse 24, an
angel is speaking to Daniel and the
angel says this, "70 weeks are
determined on your people and your holy
city to finish the transgressions, make
an end of sins, make reconciliation for
iniquity, to bring in everlasting
righteousness, to seal up the vision and
prophecy, and to anoint the most holy."
We're not going to go into what all of
that means. I'm simply going to look at
this time period 70 weeks. This is
understood to be 70 weeks of years. What
does that mean? It means each day in
this 70 weeks equals a year. So if you
take 70 weeks, 70 times 7 would be 490.
But these are not 490 literal days. They
are 490 prophetic days. meaning there
are 490
years. The 70 weeks really equals 490
years. It's a prophecy. So note what the
prophecy is saying here. Note what
happens in the very next verse
in verse 5 25. It says, "Know therefore
and understand that from the going forth
of the command to restore and to build
Jerusalem." Now pause for a second.
remember that Jerusalem has been
destroyed by Babylon.
So now in this prophecy, what they're
being told is, listen, you all are going
to go back and be able to rebuild your
city and your temple. There were several
decrees that were given to allow the
children of Israel to do this. We need
to find the decree that that is going to
start our 490
prophetic years. Notice what it says.
from the going forth of the command to
restore and to build Jerusalem unto the
Messiah, the prince. Just pause right
there.
This prophecy is telling us that if we
start from that decree and count a
certain period of time, what is that
certain period of time? It says seven
weeks and three score and two weeks. So,
so three score would be 60 weeks.
60 and two is 62 weeks. and add that
seven is 69 weeks. 69 weeks
or 483
of the 490 years is going to bring you
to the Messiah. Now, beloved, that's a
that's an amazing prophecy to actually
tell you the very year down to the very
year. If you start from this decree and
count 483
days out of the 490 days, which would
mean 483
years out of the 490 years is going to
bring you to the Messiah, the anointed
one.
Okay, that's pretty amazing, y'all.
That's pretty amazing. Let's let's check
this out. What decree was given that
allowed the Jews to rebuild their city
and their temple? The decree was given
by King Ardos Xerxes in the year 457
BC.
This decree not only allowed the
children of Israel to continue the work
of rebuilding their temple, but this
decree, you can read about it in in Ezra
7. This decree gave the children of is
of Israel autonomy allowed them to set
up their own judges and magistrates. In
other words, to operate as a fully
functioning city. So though though there
were several decrees in different years,
this is the one that gave Israel
autonomy. 457. Why is that significant?
Let me just read John Gil's commentary
on this just to just to kind of bring
this point home. Speaking on this verse,
he says, "The commencement of the weeks,
as he remarks, must be either from the
7th of Artiserxes, which falls on 457 BC
or from the 20th of Art of Xerxes, and
you are brought to the beginning of John
the Baptist preaching up uh preaching um
up the advent of the Messiah." So, let
me just break down what what he just
said because we're gonna This is
beautiful, y'all. This is divine
mathematics.
If you take 457 BC and count 69 weeks or
483 years, it brings you to 27 AD, which
is the very time which John the Baptist
is preaching at the Jordan and Jesus
comes to him to be baptized. The voice
of God is heard saying, "This is my
beloved son in whom I'm well pleased."
John the Baptist says, "Behold the lamb
of God which takes away the sins of the
world." And what does this let us know?
This is a mathematical
verification
that John the Baptist was sent of God.
We can trust what he says. And when he
points to Jesus as the lamb of God, who
also comes at the very time of Daniel's
prophecy,
listen to me y'all. If someone came
claiming to be the Messiah
60 years earlier, a hundred years
earlier, what could you know with
certainty? They could have performed all
the miracles in the world. They could
have had books and books and book they
could have shown signs and wonders. We
would know
that this could not be the Messiah. Why?
Because he doesn't fit the mathematical
chain. Are you with me? And I want you
to see what we're doing. We started from
Genesis and we're notice how we're
moving. We've moved all the way into the
New Testament. And what I'm about to
demonstrate is this chain goes all the
way to the end of time.
So anyone, let me just let me not jump
ahead of myself. Okay, so
27 AD brings us to John the Baptist and
the baptism of Jesus.
The prophecy doesn't stop there because
it goes on to say after and after three
score and two weeks. In other words,
after the 69 weeks, the Messiah shall be
cut off but not for himself.
So sometime after his baptism, the
prophecy says he was to be cut off but
not for himself. The very next verse
tells us this. It says, "And he, the
Messiah," some people get that mixed up,
that's a whole another study. But he the
Messiah shall confirm the covenant with
many for one week. And in the midst of
the week he shall cause the sacrifice
and oblation to cease. Now let me ask
you a question. A week is seven days,
right? Which would be symbolic of seven
years. So what would the midst of the
week be? Roughly three and a half years.
So let me ask you a question. What
happened to Jesus three and a half years
after he began his ministry? after he
was baptized. Did something happen to
Jesus? Did something happen to Jesus
that also caused the need for sacrifice
and offering to come to an end? Come on,
y'all. Are y'all following this? The
answer is an obvious yes. Remember Jesus
himself said these words in Matthew
26:28. He says, "For this is my blood of
the new testament which is shed for many
for the remission of sins." Let me go
back to Daniel chapter 9. He shall
confirm the covenant with many for one
week and cause the sacrifice and
oblation to cease in the midst of the
week. Jesus did just this. Three and a
half years later, he is crucified. As
Daniel stated, he is crucified. He is
cut off, but not for himself. He didn't
die for himself. He died for the world.
Are you following this?
There are mathematic there are time
signatures that verifies all the work of
God from the Old Testament all the way
into Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John. Now,
why am I pointing this out? Because I
want you to note something very
significant here. Jesus dies three and a
half years later in the middle of the
week.
You know that 50 days later, the spirit
is poured out and it's poured out on the
disciples.
Now, why is that significant?
Well, it's significant because we know
on the day of Pentecost, Acts chapter 2
verse 1 and 2, uh the Holy Spirit fell.
You can read it there. The Holy Spirit
fell and now Peter and the disciples
start prophesying.
You know what that tells us? That tells
us that Matthew, Mark, Luke, John, who
wrote 1 John, 2 John, Third John, and
the book of Revelation, James, who wrote
the book of James, Peter, who wrote 1
and 2 Peter, we can trust them. We can
trust their books. Listen to me. We can
trust their books as divine of as of
divine origin because they fit the
timestamp. They came right. They they
were they were blessed with the spirit
of God, the spirit of prophecy, if you
will, in in at the death of Jesus, at
the resurrection of Christ, I should
say. And now we can know that not only
can we trust the book, the books of
Moses. Not only can we trust the the law
and the prophets, but we can also trust
Matthew, Mark, Luke, John, James, Peter,
and the book of Revelation. Why? because
the the ones who wrote them
fulfill
a mathematical
timestamp.
If you're misunderstanding these authors
and what they say, that's a whole
different argument. Oh, the book has
contradictions. Oh, this that's a whole
different because you're not looking at
it with with the correct eyes.
But what I want you to understand,
beloved, is is we can now know that
Matthew, Mark, Luke, John, the disciples
who were with Jesus, who received the
outpouring of the Holy Spirit in the
middle of Daniel's 70th week, were
fulfilling a time prophecy.
But it doesn't stop there because
remember, it's a 70we prophecy. We
looked at the first 69 weeks. Jesus
comes at the beginning of that 70th
week. uh we we see Jesus and John the
Baptist. Three and a half years later,
Jesus dies and now you have the
outpouring of the spirit upon Matthew,
Mark, Luke, John, James, Peter, the
disciples. So, we know that the books
they wrote were divinely inspired by
God, by the Holy Spirit. But there's
three and a half years left. And
beloved, this bear with me just a moment
longer. We're getting down to the
challenge, y'all. We are almost there.
We are almost there.
If you count three and a half years
after the death of Jesus, you come to
the stoning of Stephen in 34 AD. You
want to know what's significant about
the stoning of Steven in 34 AD?
When Steven is stoned, there's a man
there by the name of Paul Saul.
In the very next chapter,
Saul
runs into Jesus. He is thrown off of his
horse. He goes blind for three days. And
when those three days are over, he is
changed from Saul to Paul. And he
becomes the author of the rest of the
New Testament, the epistles of Paul.
What does this tell us?
It tells us, beloved, that Paul
and his writings, we can trust him. Why?
because he came at the final part of the
70we prophecy. He fulfills divine
mathematics.
He is verified as a prophet. You can
just look up Wikipedia. What is the what
is what is understood to be the year
that Paul was converted? You'll see it
34 AD. Interesting. Interesting that if
you take 490 years and you start from
457 BC, you count 490 years, you will
end up with the final year being 34 AD.
Beloved, this is a prophecy that lets us
know that all the people that came in
that time period and who wrote books
during who wrote books, we can trust
them because they were fulfilling divine
time prophecies.
Why is this so significant, y'all?
Look at the chart.
Look at the chart. We got John the
Baptist.
We got Peter and the disciples in the
middle of the week. We got Paul at the
end of the week. Meaning
all the books of the New Testament,
including the book of Revelation, were
written by people who fulfilled
prophetic timestamps. Listen to me,
y'all.
Anybody can come along and say, "Oh,
this prophet, this is the person that
fulfills this pro prophecy because they
were blah blah blah blah blah." And look
at the similarities. Listen, listen,
listen.
There are millions of people who believe
that Joseph Smith
was sent of God.
Millions.
The same thing with Islam.
Do y'all see the crisis? Do you see why
I call it the mathematical prophetic
chain crisis? Because, beloved, it's
very simple. If you claim to be a
prophet, you got to be connected to the
chain. You can't just come along anytime
you want to and say, "Yeah, God gave me
a book and uh look, the whole book's
look. Mormons believe that that that an
angel came down and and just handed
Joseph Smith these plates. Hey, look."
Boom. Here it is. The whole writing,
this is divinely inspired. And millions
of people believe this and they say,
"Look at the miracles and look at how
could a man do this and that." Millions
of people believe this. But beloved,
there's a very simple test. The test is
not is the Book of Mormon uh you know
does it have truth in it? You know does
it have any error in it? Was it ever
transl was it ever uh is there any
corrupt? That's not the test.
Anybody can write a book and claim that
the book has no error in it. Claim that
the you know the book claim that the
book was divinely inspired. The true
test of divinity beloved is that you got
to fit the math the math. You got to fit
the mathematical chain. So it's a simple
question.
If this person's a prophet, show us the
time prophecy that points to this
prophet. Now remember this. If Muhammad
is supposed to be the seal of the
prophets, the greatest of all prophets.
Well beloved, listen. If God has given
timestamps for all these so-called
lesser prophets, it would there no
shadow of a doubt that if some greater
greater greater prophet was coming
towards the end of time that God would
give a time stamp to say this is when
you should be looking out. And if
someone claims to be that prophet before
this or after it, you can know that that
person was not sent by me.
Very simple challenge, y'all. Let's
let's look at the chart. You got Noah
120 years. Methuselah confirms. You got
Abraham 400 years. Moses confirms. You
have Moses giving the prophecy of the
children of Israel going into captivity
and this coming prophet. And you have
Jeremiah confirming the time element of
them going into captivity. You have
Daniel confirming the time element of
the prophet that was to come. And both
of them are fulfilled to a te.
Then in Daniel, you have you have Daniel
pointing to this end of the 70 weeks,
which brings to view John the Baptist,
Jesus, his disciples, and Paul. All of
which are are ultimately responsible for
the books of Matthew, Mark, Luke, John,
1 and 2 Peter, James, 1, 2, 3, John, the
book of Revelation, the book of Acts,
and the epistles, not Jesus himself, but
his disciples and Paul. So every book in
the Bible is accounted for in this
prophetic time chain. So the question
now is why isn't there a line
connecting to Muhammad? Why isn't there
a line connecting to Joseph Smith? Show
us the time prophecy. Don't take me to
Isaiah 42. Oh look, this is talking
about, you know, Muhama. Don't take me
to Deuteronomy 18. Oh, this is talking
about Muhammad or Joseph Smith. Show me
the time prophecy because otherwise we
can make anybody fit anything.
But you can't manipulate these times.
Beloved, if you can show in the Bible
prophecy connected in this line, not
just prophecy states that someone would
No, no, no. There's going to be a time
element because we see it all through
the scripture. We see how God operated
from Genesis all the way to Revelation.
So, show us where in the book of Daniel,
where in the book of Revelation, there
is a time prophecy that points to the
rise of the final prophet.
And if you can't do that, then I think
it's pretty clear.
I think it's pretty clear
that no matter how many miracles, no
matter how many claims of divinity, no
matter how many claims of here's why we
know God, God has not sent that
individual. You see, the challenge is
very simple. Show us the math that
points to the year 610 AD or to the year
1823.
Show us the prophecy
that points to either one of these dates
as the rise of a final prophet. The
prophet in Deuteronomy 18, if you want
to take it there. Show us the
mathematics. Show us the time prophecy
that pinpoints
this time period. If you're Muslims,
610. If you're Mormons, 1823. Show us
the prophecy that says in this year or
around this time,
God was going to bring one more, one
final prophecy, one final movement, one
final book, one final writing.
That would be the seal of the
prophecies. That would be the final
revelation of the will of God. Because
listen, if it's the final revelation of
the will of God, it's got to be pretty
big. If it's the final prophet, that's
got to be huge. I'm sure that God would
not have overlooked that while providing
all of this mathematics for everything
before it. So listen beloved, it's
really very simple.
If the math doesn't fit,
if the math doesn't fit,
then what you're teaching simply doesn't
add up.
What you're saying, what you're claiming
doesn't matter how many miracles,
doesn't matter how many claims of
divinity. It doesn't add up because
we've seen how God moves. We've seen how
God operates. We've seen his mode of
operation. He is a divine mathematician.
He is the wonderful numberer. And so if
you cannot connect the math, then we
have our answer to the dilemma.
We don't need to go into debates about,
oh, there's errors in the Bible, oh,
there's errors in the Quran, or oh, you
know, this or that, or these arguments
that really end up convincing neither
side. All we got to do is provide the
math. If you can provide the math,
we will believe.
Plain and simple.
So, there's the test.
May you be willing to follow truth
wherever it leads. Remember this y'all.
If the math doesn't add up,
then it simply doesn't add up.
Whatever you believe is the truth simply
doesn't add up. May God bless you. May
God strengthen you as you seek the truth
with all your heart, all your soul, and
all your might. God bless you.
[Music]